<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Services on Ataides.</title><link>/services/</link><description>Recent content in Services on Ataides.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Business Continuity &amp; Resilience</title><link>/services/business-resilience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/business-resilience/</guid><description>&lt;p>Business continuity and resilience are the foundation of dependable cloud environments.
Our work ensures that your infrastructure not only stays online, but continues to operate securely, predictably, and in alignment with regulatory expectations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud &amp; Data Compliance</title><link>/services/cloud-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-compliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Regulatory compliance is no longer optional, especially in cloud environments handling sensitive or regulated data.
Our advisory services help organizations align their cloud operations with legal, privacy, and security standards, from infrastructure to policy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Architecture</title><link>/services/cloud-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud architecture is the design and organization of cloud-based infrastructure that ensures scalability, resilience, security, and operational clarity.
It connects business objectives with technical precision to create an environment that performs under pressure — and evolves with confidence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Security</title><link>/services/cloud-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-security/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud environments demand security that is not only robust, but scalable, automated, and compliant.
We help organizations design and implement security architectures that are resilient by design, audit-ready, and aligned with business risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FinOps &amp; Cloud Cost Optimization</title><link>/services/finops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/finops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud costs spiral quickly without structure.
We help organizations bring financial discipline to the cloud, aligning spending with business value through FinOps practices, visibility frameworks, and architectural decisions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Governance &amp; Risk Mapping</title><link>/services/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/governance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud governance isn&amp;rsquo;t bureaucracy — it’s how you scale securely, sustainably, and with clarity.
We help organizations map technical and compliance risks, define policies, and implement governance structures that align with business strategy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>