<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Services on Ataides.</title><link>/services/</link><description>Recent content in Services on Ataides.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Governance &amp; Role Architecture</title><link>/services/cloud-governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-governance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Governance is not bureaucracy, it’s institutional discipline for cloud environments. Ataides delivers neutral, audit-aligned cloud governance architecture focused on control, clarity, and compliance readiness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FinOps Architecture &amp; Cost Accountability</title><link>/services/finops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/finops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud efficiency is not about cost-cutting, it’s about governance, visibility, and sustainable growth. Ataides helps organizations implement a FinOps architecture that aligns finance, engineering, and leadership around accountable, purposeful cloud usage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Regulatory Compliance Architecture</title><link>/services/regulatory-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/regulatory-compliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Compliance is not a checklist, it is an architectural discipline. Ataides helps organizations design cloud environments that are secure, traceable, and audit-aligned from the ground up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resilience &amp; Continuity Readiness</title><link>/services/resilience-continuity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/resilience-continuity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Availability is not resilience, and SLAs are not strategy. Ataides helps organizations assess and strengthen their cloud environments for real-world disruption, ensuring continuity with precision, visibility, and accountability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Executive Cloud Advisory</title><link>/services/cloud-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Strategy is not about tools, it’s about foresight, alignment, and trust. Ataides provides vendor-neutral cloud advisory for leadership teams making critical decisions under complexity, risk, or regulatory scrutiny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Architecture &amp; Resilience</title><link>/services/cloud-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-security/</guid><description>&lt;p>Security is not an add-on, it is a foundational layer of trust, resilience, and institutional integrity. Ataides helps organizations implement security architectures that are resilient by design, audit-aligned, and proportional to business risk.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>