<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on Ataides.</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on Ataides.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 16:11:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Business Continuity &amp; Resilience</title><link>/services/business-resilience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/business-resilience/</guid><description>&lt;p>Business continuity and resilience are the foundation of dependable cloud environments.
Our work ensures that your infrastructure not only stays online, but continues to operate securely, predictably, and in alignment with regulatory expectations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud &amp; Data Compliance</title><link>/services/cloud-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-compliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Regulatory compliance is no longer optional, especially in cloud environments handling sensitive or regulated data.
Our advisory services help organizations align their cloud operations with legal, privacy, and security standards, from infrastructure to policy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Architecture</title><link>/services/cloud-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-architecture/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud architecture is the design and organization of cloud-based infrastructure that ensures scalability, resilience, security, and operational clarity.
It connects business objectives with technical precision to create an environment that performs under pressure — and evolves with confidence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Security</title><link>/services/cloud-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-security/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud environments demand security that is not only robust, but scalable, automated, and compliant.
We help organizations design and implement security architectures that are resilient by design, audit-ready, and aligned with business risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FinOps &amp; Cloud Cost Optimization</title><link>/services/finops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/finops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud costs spiral quickly without structure.
We help organizations bring financial discipline to the cloud, aligning spending with business value through FinOps practices, visibility frameworks, and architectural decisions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Governance &amp; Risk Mapping</title><link>/services/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/governance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud governance isn&amp;rsquo;t bureaucracy — it’s how you scale securely, sustainably, and with clarity.
We help organizations map technical and compliance risks, define policies, and implement governance structures that align with business strategy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 16:11:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ataides is an independent consultant specializing in &lt;strong>Cloud Architecture&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Compliance&lt;/strong>. With experience across &lt;strong>AWS&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>GCP&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Azure&lt;/strong>, our work is rooted in precision, discretion, and neutrality - delivering outcomes that align both with business goals and regulatory standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This company was founded on a belief:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Infrastructure should not only perform — it should protect, govern, and endure.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We work with clients who understand that cloud is not just a technical layer, but a strategic asset. That uptime means nothing without &lt;strong>integrity&lt;/strong>. And that scaling fast is irrelevant if you can&amp;rsquo;t scale &lt;strong>safely&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 16:09:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>We operate with discretion, clarity, and purpose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are exploring improvements in cloud architecture, compliance, or security - or would like to schedule a confidential consultation - we invite you to reach out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We serve clients globally. Meetings are scheduled based on mutual availability, typically within the following windows (UTC-3):&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>Day&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Availability&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Monday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Tuesday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Wednesday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Thursday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Friday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Saturday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>By request only&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Sunday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Closed&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="contact-form">Contact Form&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To initiate a conversation or request a consultation, please complete the form below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Page Not Found</title><link>/404/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/404/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="this-page-doesnt-exist">This page doesn’t exist.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The page you’re looking for might have been moved, renamed, or never existed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you believe this is an error, or if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to reach a specific resource, feel free to &lt;a href="/contact">contact us&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/">→ Return to Homepage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/privacy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Effective Date:&lt;/strong> April 6, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lucas de Ataides Barreto Consultoria em Tecnologia da Informação LTDA&lt;/strong> (&amp;quot;&lt;strong>we&lt;/strong>&amp;quot;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>our&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>us&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, disclose, and safeguard your personal information when you visit our website, &lt;code>https://ataides.com&lt;/code>, and when you engage with us through our contact forms, email communications, or consulting services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This policy complies with the &lt;strong>Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados (LGPD)&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/strong>, and other applicable data protection regulations, including but not limited to the &lt;strong>California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terms of Service</title><link>/tos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tos/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Effective Date:&lt;/strong> April 6, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Welcome to &lt;strong>Lucas de Ataides Barreto Consultoria em Tecnologia da Informação LTDA&lt;/strong> (“we”, “our”, or “us”). These Terms of Service (“Terms”) govern your use of our website, &lt;code>https://ataides.com&lt;/code>, and any content, materials, or communications made available through it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By accessing or using this site, you agree to be bound by these Terms. If you do not agree with them, please do not use the site.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>