<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on Ataides.</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on Ataides.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 16:11:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Governance &amp; Role Architecture</title><link>/services/cloud-governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-governance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Governance is not bureaucracy, it’s institutional discipline for cloud environments. Ataides delivers neutral, audit-aligned cloud governance architecture focused on control, clarity, and compliance readiness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notary</title><link>/open-source/notary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/open-source/notary/</guid><description>&lt;p>Compliance doesn&amp;rsquo;t start with the audit, it starts with how you store proof. Notary is an open-source, secure evidence vault designed to preserve the integrity, confidentiality, and traceability of technical compliance data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blueprints</title><link>/open-source/blueprints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/open-source/blueprints/</guid><description>&lt;p>A curated collection of Terraform modules that implement security and compliance best practices by default, with embedded metadata, audit-ready documentation, and cloud-agnostic design patterns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FinOps Architecture &amp; Cost Accountability</title><link>/services/finops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/finops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cloud efficiency is not about cost-cutting, it’s about governance, visibility, and sustainable growth. Ataides helps organizations implement a FinOps architecture that aligns finance, engineering, and leadership around accountable, purposeful cloud usage.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Regulatory Compliance Architecture</title><link>/services/regulatory-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/regulatory-compliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Compliance is not a checklist, it is an architectural discipline. Ataides helps organizations design cloud environments that are secure, traceable, and audit-aligned from the ground up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resilience &amp; Continuity Readiness</title><link>/services/resilience-continuity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/resilience-continuity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Availability is not resilience, and SLAs are not strategy. Ataides helps organizations assess and strengthen their cloud environments for real-world disruption, ensuring continuity with precision, visibility, and accountability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Executive Cloud Advisory</title><link>/services/cloud-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Strategy is not about tools, it’s about foresight, alignment, and trust. Ataides provides vendor-neutral cloud advisory for leadership teams making critical decisions under complexity, risk, or regulatory scrutiny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Architecture &amp; Resilience</title><link>/services/cloud-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/cloud-security/</guid><description>&lt;p>Security is not an add-on, it is a foundational layer of trust, resilience, and institutional integrity. Ataides helps organizations implement security architectures that are resilient by design, audit-aligned, and proportional to business risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 16:11:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ataides is a neutral and independent cloud advisory firm. We specialize in Cloud Architecture, Security, and Compliance, helping organizations build audit-ready infrastructure with institutional-grade discipline across AWS, GCP, and Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This company was founded on a belief:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We don’t just engineer for performance, we engineer for resilience, sovereignty, and institutional trust.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We work with clients who understand that cloud is not just a technical layer, but a strategic asset. That uptime means nothing without &lt;strong>integrity&lt;/strong>. And that scaling fast is irrelevant if you can&amp;rsquo;t scale &lt;strong>safely&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 16:09:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>We operate with neutrality, discretion, and institutional clarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If your organization is evaluating improvements in cloud architecture, security posture, or regulatory alignment, Ataides offers confidential, high-trust engagements with global reach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meetings are scheduled based on mutual availability, typically within the following windows (UTC-3):&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>Day&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Availability&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Monday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Tuesday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Wednesday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Thursday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Friday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>9:00am – 6:00pm&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Saturday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>By request only&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Sunday&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Closed&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="contact-form">Contact Form&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To request a private consultation, please complete the short intake form below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/faq/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ataides works with organizations that demand institutional-grade trust in their cloud environments, including those in regulated sectors, rapid growth phases, or under strategic scrutiny.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some of the most common questions we receive:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-do-organizations-trust-ataides">Why do organizations trust Ataides?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trust is not given, it&amp;rsquo;s earned through discipline, neutrality, and integrity. Ataides operates independently, without incentives from vendors or platforms. Our advisors are certified, experienced, and focused on long-term alignment with your risk, governance, and compliance needs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How We Work</title><link>/how-we-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/how-we-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our process is built on discretion, structure, and institutional clarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ataides works with organizations that demand strategic alignment, security assurance, and regulatory integrity, from architecture design to board-level insight.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-discovery--qualification">1. Discovery &amp;amp; Qualification&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We begin with a strategic intake session to understand your architecture, compliance obligations, internal structure, and business risk posture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You’ll walk away with:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A shared understanding of objectives&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initial risk posture overview&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fit and feasibility assessment&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="2-scoped-proposal--agreement">2. Scoped Proposal &amp;amp; Agreement&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If there’s alignment, we formalize the engagement with:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Page Not Found</title><link>/404/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/404/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="this-page-doesnt-exist">This page doesn’t exist.&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The page you’re looking for might have been moved, renamed, or never existed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you believe this is an error, or if you&amp;rsquo;re trying to reach a specific resource, feel free to &lt;a href="/contact">contact us&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/">→ Return to Homepage&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/privacy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Effective Date:&lt;/strong> May 10, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lucas de Ataides Barreto Consultoria em Tecnologia da Informação LTDA&lt;/strong> (&amp;quot;&lt;strong>Ataides&lt;/strong>&amp;quot;, &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>we&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>our firm&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;) is committed to safeguarding your personal data. This Privacy Policy outlines how we collect, use, disclose, and protect information when you interact with our website (&lt;code>https://ataides.com&lt;/code>) or engage with our advisory services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Policy complies with applicable data protection laws, including the &lt;strong>Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados (LGPD)&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/strong>, and the &lt;strong>California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terms of Service</title><link>/tos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tos/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Effective Date:&lt;/strong> May 10, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Welcome to &lt;strong>Lucas de Ataides Barreto Consultoria em Tecnologia da Informação LTDA&lt;/strong> (“&lt;strong>Ataides&lt;/strong>”, “we”, or “our firm”). These Terms of Service (“Terms”) govern your use of our website (&lt;code>https://ataides.com&lt;/code>) and any information, content, or communication provided through it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-website-purpose">1. Website Purpose&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This website presents information about Ataides&amp;rsquo; cloud advisory services, including governance, security, and regulatory compliance. All content is for general informational purposes and does not constitute legal or technical advice unless expressly established in a signed engagement agreement.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>